Curriculum vital

Name: VIJAY SAHU

Permanent Address: -

239 Tirupati dham kani pura road

Ujjain: 456010 Mobile No.: +91-9977548778 E-mail: vijays1988.953@gmail.com

9993048778

Career Objective:

To work with an esteemed organization to prove my potential along with the growth and profitability of the organization, being able to achieve new heights in my career.

Skill and Summary of Work Experience:

Commerce Graduate & MBA with over 17 years of work experience in Banking & Finance sector. Single point of contact with the Customer; handholding through the process of NBFC, Customer Service, Cross sell & Direct Sell; offering world class services.

Work Experience:

Organization Poonawalla Fincorp Limited : **Duration** April 2012 to till date : **Designation & Location** Asst Manager, Ujjain (M. P.) :

Current Responsibilities: Customer service, Direct Sales Officer,& Branch Operation & Accounts (Feb **2020 to Present)** (Home loan, ABF, SME, Insurance)

Operations (Car ,Suvidha ,tractor, Home Loan)

- Pre & Post Sanction file checking and move to credit que.
- > File disbursement and payment approve in branch level to dealer by RTGS/ NEFT/ Remote cheque
- PDD (RC & Invoice) updation in system
- Working in Magma fin corp online software oracle.
- CRM Fresh case login in generate file no. By POS Software and
- HL file checking and login in system

Previous Responsibilities: Customer service officer & Direct Sales Officer (2015 to Jan 2021)

Direct Sales

Looking after the Direct Sales of Home Loan, ABF, SME & Health Insurance

- Managing 1 RM Insurance
- > Leads Generate Through Walking Customer/ Telecalling & Then Coordinate with Sales Team
- > Coordinate with 15 ABF FOS and 5 Home Loan RM about Leads allocated to Them
- Also Following Customer to Complete Documentation which Lead them for Disbursal process.

Achievements:

- Achieved 1Crore continuously PAN India Topper .
- Achieved First Branch to done 1 Lakh Business in Health Insurance PAN India

Customer Services

Good customer service is the lifeblood of any business. The essence of good customer service is forming a relationship with customers – a relationship that individual customer feels that he would like to pursue.

- Warm welcome with genuine smile. Ask Customer for assistance to provide satisfactory solution.
- > Engages with customer through well defined scripts and profilers during or post the services to drive sales
- Handle customer queries for all the products and accounts.
- Leads generation & Customer retention.
- Providing & explaining various deliverables to the customers like Statement of Account, Repayment Amortization schedule, SOA, TDS certificate, IT certificate, NOC, Original property papers s in case of normal maturity and foreclose

- Handling swapping, switching, refund process, Foreclose process, retrieval of documents, OD calculation, & waiver request process.
- > Ensure speedy resolution of customer queries within defined TAT to provide seamless service experience
- > Try to identify customer's needs and offer solutions for their queries

Previous Responsibilities: Branch ops Accountant/ & HR & Admin Coordinator (2012 to 2015)

Operations (Car ,Suvidha,tractor, Home Loan)

- Pre & Post Sanction file checking and move to credit que.
- > File disbursement and payment approve in branch level to dealer by RTGS/ NEFT/ Remote cheque
- > PDD (RC & Invoice) updation in system
- Working in Magma fin corp online software oracle.
- CRM Fresh case login in generate file no. By POS Software and
- HL file checking and login in system

Branch Accountant cum Cashier & HR Coordinator

- To Collect Cash & Cheques from the customer and deposit in to the bank
- > Controlled Cash and Cheques worth Rs Five to Six crores every month
- > Prepare and send daily, weekly and monthly MIS reports such as accruals, petty cash report, Branch compliance report, E-DCR etc on time.
- > Track expenses at the branch level and ensure that fake bills are not entered into the petty cash system
- Managed file and data to feed information into online software oracle computer system
- Coordinating HR and Admin Department.
- > Joining and exit formalities of employees
- > Reported to the Regional State Head regarding various MIS.
- Achieved the Audit requirement of last three Audit of the Branch.

Banking Operations

- Receipt and payment of cash transactions along with cash remittance to CMS.
- > Perform daily Clearing operations likes transfer, Inward/outward clearing, CMS cash/Chq.

Achievements:

- Got Best executive for Cross Selling Activity at Branch.
- > Received many appreciation mails from seniors for cross selling and Idea generation for cost saving.
- > Appreciation mails received from customers to render better services as well as product offered as per need.

Administrative:

- > Handhold new joinees in the department,
- Focus on Existing relationship value and New Customer acquisition
- > Processing of vendor bill Payment. Maintenance and publication of Various MIS on Regional level.
- > Ensure various report generation of cash.
- Maintenance of key register, deliverables registers, inventory registers etc on a daily basis
- > Ensure error free records \vouchers \reports maintenance and archival..

Previous Work Experience:

Organization : CITI Financial Consumer Finance India Ltd. at Ujjain

Duration : Jan 2009 to March 2012 **Designation & Location** : Agency Team leader

Job Responsibilities:

- > Cash & Chq. Collection handling
- > Responsible for the overall reduction in delinquency
- ➤ Responsible of 0 to 180 + Buckets collection
- ➤ Looking after collection of (TL,HL & PL)
- ➤ Legal Related all works
- ➤ All Collection related MIS Updation

- Customer regular follow-up before EMI & after EMI Overdue
- Critical customer visit for resolution
- Daily Review of all Executive for Daily MTD Target. .
- Maintaining the monthly target to achieve yearly target.
- Collection report to Collection Manager

Previous Work Experience:

Organization : Parsavnath Developers Ltd Ujjain (Residential Township Project.)

Duration: Jun 2008 to Dec 2008

Designation & Location : Executive (Sales) Ujjain (M. P.)

Job Responsibilities:

- > Giving proper attention to the customer and increase the numbers of satisfied customers.
- Customer A/c handling, Commercial Operations.
- Handling and updating about project details
- Supervision of team of Officer Part time Officers for operation activities.

Previous Work Experience:

Organization : CITI Financial Consumer Finance India Ltd.at Ujjain

Duration: Jun 2006 to April 2008

Designation & Location : Executive (Operation & Processing) Ujjain (M. P.)

Job Responsibilities:

- Credit Operations like Reference No. Generation, Internal Dedupe.
- > CPV Allocation, Disbursed Case Cheques Printing, Exceptions Resolutions.
- > File Dispatching, Query resolutions, increasing customer base.
- > Product Awareness and selling Personal Loan , Two wheeler loan

Personal Attributes:

- Good communicational & analytical skills.
- ➤ Hard working with positive attitude. Ability to handle volumes
- Willingness to walk the extra mile to achieve excellence
- Always ensure committed Services after sales
- > Continuous knowledge upgradation through self learning and going through e-circulars.

Educational Qualification:

- PGDCA (Makhan Lal Chaturvedi)
- MBA From Punjab University 2010
- ➤ B. Com. from Vikram University Ujjain 2008.
- Passed Higher Secondary Examination (Commerce) from M.P. Board. 2005
- Passed High School Examination from M.P. Board 2003

IT Skills:

- Proficient in MS Office. Windows 2007
- Internet

Hobbies:

- Traveling
- Gardening

PERSONAL DETAILS

Date of Birth : 24th Nov 1988
Marital Status : Married
Gender : Male

Languages Known : Hindi & English

I hereby declare that all the above information furnished by me is correct and true to the best of my belief and knowledge.

Date:

Place: Ujjain

(Vijay Sahu)